little YouTube world I am going live so
that I do this in one take because
that's what I want to do I don't want to
spend a long time doing it so
introducing the hope cafe so the Hope
Cafe is a Facebook group where we are
hosting the conversation that will be
the powerful tool needed to create a
better world for everyone so a few weeks
ago I encountered the concept of a World
Cafe which is a powerful dialogue tool
for a large group of people to be able
to have an intimate conversation to be
able to hear ideas and get your ideas
across and yet have a conversation with
the greater group as well so how it
works in the physical world the World
Cafe is around cafe style tables people
get together in groups of 4 to 5 and
have a conversation about a meaningful
question an open-ended question that
nobody knows the exact answer to there's
no wrong answer to the question it's
just you sharing your opinion your ideas
around a table with other people doing
the same then after 20 minutes the
conversation ends one person stays to
host that conversation that happened at
that table and the other group
conversation lists dispersed into the
room where they becomes seeds for that
conversation at each table is paper and
pens that people can make a visual
representation of what they've talked
about for other people to to be able to
more easily understand what was talked
to at that table
everyone is also asked invited to look
for the greater meaning look for the
bigger conversation the threads that are
throughout all the conversations they're
part of around the same question and in
so doing you're able to brainstorm on a
massive scale and create action plans
that actually because they came through
the group people want to take part in
implementing and so the Hope cafe on
Facebook is our current version of
hosting the conversation
in a world cafe format on existing
platforms well we have the conversations
needed to create the platform design for
that type of conversation where anybody
can ask a question have a group of
people come together and brainstorm it
where we'd have the questions that are
asked about our cooperative to move it
forward and be able to get people's
feedback on what is and isn't working
for them and so people are invited to
all you have to do as an individual is
bring yourself to the table exactly as
you are with your level of knowledge
your level of experience bring you that
is the greatest gift you can bring to
the conversation also you do not have to
have a conversation with any single
individual like you don't you don't get
to say that someone's unable to
participate in the greater conversation
you can say I'm not going to participate
in a conversation with that person and
creating the tools to actually
facilitate that so that more of our
energy is going towards the conversation
and not the interpersonal drama that can
occur that doesn't need to occur
there'll be some that occurs because it
helps us move forward but we are just
going to continually perfect the
experience of having the conversation
creating the tools to make to create
action out of that while never reaching
perfection it's just constantly asking
what's not working and how do we get it
to work on a massive scale and so
speaking of that I hosted the first hope
cafe that was going to be around what
like a virtual table of us having a
video conversation it would have been
just one table because that was only
gonna be four of us and nobody showed up
to it and so in that space I've done
enough interpersonal work where I don't
make that mean anything I'm like right
so the question is why why didn't people
show up why and having the conversation
but one didn't work about the timeslot
about your life at general about I had a
bad day well you're allowed to not come
if you have a bad day you're also
allowed to come and have a bad day
you're allowed to bring your bad days to
the table that is who you are in the
moment and so both of those things are
fine but then we needed like what
doesn't work for me is sitting around
talking whom have you to conversation
with one person so I need to be able to
know that people are gonna be at the
table when we host the host because I
want to have the conversation and so
both I found a way to have that
conversation without people being at the
table which I posted the question which
is this week's question is what makes a
conversation enjoyable to you and
invited the members of the hope cafe
which I will link in the description so
you can join if you would like as well
as you can just comment here and say
what is what makes a conversation
enjoyable to you and every week I'm
gonna have a different conversation
Monday will be a new one will host it
first during that hour and then I will
post it for the for the greater group to
also give feedback on people that aren't
available during that two to three times
lot Civic standard time can also be part
of the conversation and once humanity
has a platform that they know they can
trust because they're part of creating
it and can be as involved as they want
to be once we have the platform designed
for a meaningful productive conversation
our world changes because from that code
those conversations we are going to
create so many different kinds of tools
that we then all have access to and the
more we let go of needing to participate
in every step of every process because
we've been shown that humanity doing it
is is trustworthy because we've had the
conversations on what makes it
trustworthy input the systems in place
that we've funded it together and we
know we have a voice that we can improve
any of the tools were part of we also
never have to improve them they can just
enjoy everyone else improving them we
are going to have a fun easy peaceful
revolution and it starts and is the
conversation and so if you want like I
said if you want to get involved in the
actual conversation how it's designed
Facebook is the way to go
hope cafe and like I said they'll be a
link or I will be posting weekly here
the same question and I will be
answering the question other people can
answer the classroom which is not so
well of a dialog of a conversation but
it's the best we have on YouTube moment
I'm also trying a trial on periscope
where I've been for a year and half
basically no viewers um backs on and so
what I'm doing is I'm hosting from 9:00
to 9:30 or from 9:00 to 10:00 at least
9:00 to 9:30 with the same question
twice a week and having people whoever
comes on and participates will be the
first like whoever first comes on and
calls in is the people who are
participate for that half an hour and as
there are more and more people wanting
to participate we will branch off into
other channels and have other people
host the same question with the hashtag
hope cafe and people who want to
participate can either come in view and
just watch and see how it goes or they
can request to be part of it and go and
become part of one of the channels and
pollen and if we need to we can make
more tools around coordinating that so
that if there's like hundreds of
channels oh no what a problem to have
that people know where they're going and
and we're not dissipating the energy but
I'm excited because having people get
together have a conversation that's fun
and enjoyable so they want to
participate and allowing us to fail in
the right direction where failure is
just a step towards success everything
that goes wrong is a learning experience
to have it go right in the future
everything and from that energy we're
gonna create the solutions that give
every human being who wants one an
abundant life and a peaceful life and a
life that is designed so that they're
able to live their best life and give
their best self to the world by having
those people at the table telling us
what they need to do that not me
deciding what everyone needs people at
this table just having a conversation
what's working what's not working how
can we make it work for you so that is
what it's going on in the world and if
you are watching this you happen to
randomly find it please like and
subscribe
YouTube's not my main mode of doing it
so I haven't been keeping up but if
there's people actually commenting here
and actually answering the question
which again it is what what makes a
conversation enjoyable to you I will put
this I will come on more ticker please
like it
get the Bell been notified